Buchi Michelle Okonicha

Eti-Osa, Lagos, Nigeria



michelle.okonicha.190081@gmail.com



08169391259



linkedin.com/in/buchi-michelleokonicha-0a3b2b194

Summary

My interest and love lies in building digital products with thoughtful user experience and resolving issues, fixing problems simply and critically.

I have built applications spanning around different industries. Web3/ DAO real time application, e-commerce fashion application, crypto friendly application and worked with tools and varying components to produce the best of programming and software development. This I have achieved over time in years.

I build broadly frontend applications and have used different libraries and frameworks ranging from React to Next. is to Vue is to Nuxt. is with attainable goals of building applications for sustainable technology. Also vast knowledge in database management and handling tools and service applications.

When you come to a room full of techies, look for the one with the most technical assignment, then you have found me.

I am currently aligning my career towards Technical product management and Director of software engineering as my communication skills combined with my topnotch technical skills in writing codes and words, understanding of agile methodologies are great for it and I have led groups and managed project teams and always willing to put in the work in seeing successful completion of projects.

My core strength lies in front-end development for web applications and responsive web design engineering with Typescript, JavaScript and C, React, Next.js, Vue.js and Nuxt.js. Also collaborating thoughtfully with clear communication and apt updates to ensure a thriving system.

I would most certainly love a conversation with you if you are interested in any of these and I hope to find aligning values as well.

Experience



Software Engineer

Aricah

May 2022 - Present (2 months +)

Building Africa's largest ecosystem of tech newbies.

Women Techmakers

May 2022 - Present (2 months +)

≒ Open Source Developer

Layer5

2022 - Present (6 months +)

Frontend Engineer

Kwek

2021 - 2022 (2 years)

Worked on implementing an ecommerce platform focused on the fashion industry from clothings to shoes to everything fashion inclusive. Implemented the cart feature to enable users pick as many items as possible also the payment feature, ratings and seller side of the application using Graphql to query data.

:: Frontend Engineer

ZuriChat

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021 (8 months)

A web3/DAO system of management for real-time communication. Interesting work here that involved real time communication with centrifugal, building an enabling communication route for efficient remote work experience and collaboration. A combination of slack and the web3 effect.

Frontend Developer

HNG Internship

2020 - 2021 (2 years)

collaborative system building numerous mini applications.

Frontend Developer

Aquiles Solutions 2019 - 2020 (2 years)

Education

🐯 University of Nigeria, Nsukka

Bachelor's degree, BS.c

Harvard University

Certification, Computer Science 2021 - 2022

Y Combinator

Startup school 2021 - 2022

Quantic School of Business and Technology

Mini-MBA, Customer Discovery

(A) freeCodeCamp

Software Engineering, Computer Software Engineering

Simplilearn Alumni

certification, Computer Programming, Specific Applications Jan 2022 - 2022

Zuri Training Institute

Software Engineering, Computer Software Engineering Mar 2021 - Present

Simplilearn Alumni

Certification, Computer Programming, Specific Applications Jan 2020 - Present

Licenses & Certifications

- IAB Digital Marketing and Media Foundations Certification Google Digital Skills For Africa
- Customer Discovery Quantic School of Business and Technology
- Early stage Entrepreneurship Savvy
- IBM Certified Application Developer Programming with IBM Enterprise PL/I IBM
- GitHub Profile Ownership Verified (Ranked in top 6.40%) as of 2021-11-24 -

TechieRank

GitHub Username: Michellebuchiokonicha

GitHub Profile Ownership Verified (Ranked in top 6.40%) | Stack Overflow Profile Ownership Verified as of 2021-11-24 - TechieRank

GitHub Username: Michellebuchiokonicha | Stack Overflow ID: 7353524

Skills

React.js • JavaScript • SQL • Software Testing • Software Development • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • HTML5 • Communication • Management • TypeScript

Honors & Awards

Nominee, Software Developer (Front-end) of the year - Techtrend Africa
Nov 2021